Kiley, Dan (Dan Urban), 1912-2004. Papers of Dan Kiley: An Inventory.
Kiley, Dan (Dan Urban), 1912-2004. Papers of Dan Kiley: An Inventory.
ca.1941-ca.1995
Special Collections, Frances Loeb Library, Graduate School of Design, Harvard University.
DES.1995.0004.006399835
Kiley, Dan (Dan Urban), 1912-2004.
500 linear feet
Extent is approximate
This collection includes landscape drawings representing the work of Dan Kiley, and The Office of Dan Kiley, ca.1941-ca.1995.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Dan Kiley, 1995.
Conditions on Use and Access
Contact Special Collections Department, Frances Loeb Library, Harvard University Graduate School of Design.
History
Born in Boston in 1912, Dan Kiley attended the Harvard University Graduate School of Design in the mid-1930s. In 1939, with fellow landscape architects Garret Eckbo and James Rose, he published a seminal manifesto on modernist landscape architecture in three parts related to the urban, rural, and primeval environments. He served in the Office of Strategic Services during World War II. At the end of World War II, Kiley designed the courtroom where the Nuremberg Trials were held. In 1951 he established the Office of Dan Kiley in Charlotte, Vermont, where he worked for more than forty years until his death in 2004.
Considered the father of modern landscape architecture in the United States, Dan Kiley combined modern design ideals with classical principles in hundreds of projects in the United States and worldwide. Among his projects, many with notable architects, include the Gateway Arch in St. Louis (Missouri), the Miller House Garden (Indiana), and the US Air Force Academy (Colorado) where he worked with Eero Saarinen on all three projects; the Ford Foundation's headquarters in Manhattan with Kevin Roche; and the National Gallery of Art's East Wing in Washington D.C. with I. M. Pei. His overseas projects include the landscape of La Defense in Paris. Kiley was awarded in September 1997 the National Medal of the Arts, the highest honor that can be bestowed upon an artist in the United States.
The collection includes landscape architecture drawings for a broad representation of his landscape designs, including site plans, planting plans, and topographical maps gifted by Dan Kiley in 1995. It should be noted that a large amount of drawings and several hundred boxes of job files remained in Vermont to be gifted at a later date, but because of a tragic fire sparked by lightning in 2005 (that completely destroyed the structure that housed the Office of Dan Kiley and its contents) these files have been lost.
The collection is arranged in a single series of 483 files in tubes, 128 files in folders, and 2 boxes of materials listed by job number. The collection also includes an addendum with a few materials related to a GSD symposium and exhibition: "Dan Kiley, Landscape Architect: The First Two Decades" mounted at the GSD in 1997.
- Landscape Architecture Drawings, / Date(s): ca. 1941 - ca. 1995; 0000; / Quantity: ca. 483 tubes; 128 folders; 2 boxes / Medium: Mixed / Support: Mixed
  Note: The series is arranged by job number, plus an addendum at the end of the series with a few materials related to a GSD symposium and exhibition: Dan Kiley, Landscape Architect: The First Two Decades.
  - Charles Collier House, / Date(s): 1941; Folder: 0009; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 92x61cm. / Medium: Xerographic print / Support: Paper
    Note: Print (reduced?) of an early Kiley domestic landscape.
    Scale: Unknown.
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS,p. 204 for Kiley's comments on this job.
  - Ralph Hetzel Property, / Date(s): 1941 - 1942; Folder: 0015; / Quantity: 4 / Dimensions: 80x61cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Mixed
    Note: Original drawings in pencil, with later blueprints of same. Location indicated as "Alexandria, V" on drawings.
    Scale: Varies.
  - Edward Hollander Residence, / Date(s): 1941; Folder: 0018; / Quantity: 2 / Dimensions: <106x72cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Preliminary and subsequent site and planting plans.
    Scale: 18"=1'.
    Location of associated materials: See also #43 (Edward Hollander Blackout Room) and #19 (Clarke Foreman Place). The latter is adjacent to the Hollander property.
  - Clark Foreman Residence, / Date(s): 1941; Folder: 0019; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 100x65cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site and planting plan with perspective drawings.
    Note: Characterized in the Works as "...this residential design focuses on the delineation of programmed outdoor rooms ..." (p. 204).
    Location of associated materials: Cf. Also, #18, Edward Hollander Residence", adjacent to the Foreman property.
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS ..., p. 204, for Kiley's comments on this job.
  - Moyer Residence, / Date(s): 1941; Folder: 0023; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 59x48cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Indicated on ODK project list as "Mrs. Herbert S. Moyer."
    Scale: 1/4"=1'.
  - Edmund Bacon Property, / Date(s): 1941 - 1942; Folder: 0028; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 64x36cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Drawing dated 1942.
    Scale: 1"=10'-0".
  - Walker Bleakney Residence, / Date(s): 1941 - 1942; Folder: 0030; / Quantity: 2 / Dimensions: <132x53cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing Paper
    Note: Planting and landscape pls; drawing dated 2-27-42.
    Scale: 1"=10'.
    Published in: Progressive Architecture, September 1947, v. 28, pp. 56-58. Illustrations include photographs antedating landscape installation.
  - Stanley Surry Residence, / Date(s): 1941 - 1942; Folder: 0031; / Quantity: 9 / Dimensions: <106x61cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Mixed
    Note: Pencil on trace, accompanied by blueline prints of same, dated 1942.
  - Frederick Beckman Residence, / Date(s): 1941; Folder: 0033; / Quantity: 12 / Dimensions: <97x70cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site development and planting plans; some drawings indicate alternative location of Skillman, NJ.
    Location of originals or duplicates: Folder includes rduced xerogaphic copies of each drawing.
    Published in: "Brookhouse ...", Progressive Architecture, v. 27, pp.75-90, September 1946.
  - Lily Pond Housing Project, / Date(s): 1942; Folder: 0042; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 126x100cm. / Medium: Blueprint / Support: Paper
    Note: Site plan for a wartime housing project; drawn and checked by Dan Kiley.
    Scale: 1"=40'.
    Published in: Anita Berrizbeita, "Early Housing Projects ...", Daniel Urban Kiley, The Early Gardens, pp. 21-36.
    Published in: Cf. also: Stern, Robert A.M., George Howe (1975), pp. 197-198 and figs. 128-129.
  - Edward Hollander Blackout Room, / Date(s): 1942 - 1943; Folder: 0043; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 79x61cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Dan Kiley architectural drawings related to wartime renovation/adaptation of residential interior.
    Location of associated materials: Cf. #18, Edward Hollander Residence.
  - Nuremberg Courthouse, / Date(s): 1945; Tube: 0048; / Quantity: 44 / Dimensions: 65x46cm. / Medium: Stats (copies) / Support: Paper
    Note: As Chief of Design of the OSS Presentation Branch, Kiley designed the required installations and rinterior renovations of the Nuremberg Courthouse in preparation for the trials of the accused German war criminals.
    Note: The technical requirements for translation, recording and filming necessitated the most advanced and complex use of related equipment.
    Note: Kiley's work also included the design of press and information areas and a variety of other adaptations.
    Note: This file includes selected reproductions of drawings of the structure dating from 1917 as well as reproductions of Kiley's working drawings and plans.
    Note: "Dan Kiley" was among the dramatized "real people" depicted in a TNT miniseries, The Nuremberg Trials, which aired in July 2000.
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS ..., p. 204, for Kiley's comments on the assignment.
  - John Atherton / Red House, / Date(s): 1946; Tube: 0101; / Quantity: 31 / Dimensions: <82x61cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Sheets numbered #1-31, sheets #11, 14, 16 and 28 lacking.
    Note: Although the Red House was undertaken in 1946, these drawings are dated 1948-49.
    Note: "One of the first projects I did after the war ..."--DK, Complete Works, p. 205.
  - Jefferson National Expansion Memorial, / Date(s): 1947 - 1963; Tube: 0134; / Quantity: 17 / Dimensions: <333x103cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Mixed
    Note: A mixed files, including perspective drawings, planting plans, and prints related to the original 1947 competition and subsequent changes.
    Note: Kiley's plans (with a variety of Park Service changes) became the setting for Saarinen's Gateway Arch.
    Location of associated materials: There is a substantial literature dealing with the design and construction of the Gateway Arch; cf. also the Architectural Competition ... Program (1947).
    Published in: Among the most useful journal contributions are: "Jefferson National Expansion Memorial Competition", Architectural Forum, March 1948, pp. 14-16, "Kiley Revisted", Landscape Architecture, August 1998, 88:8, pp. 58-61,86-89,
    Published in: "St. Louis Waterfront Revisited", Landscape Architecture, April 1964, 54:4, pp. 182-186, "Monumentality/Mentality", Oppositions, Fall 1982, 25, pp. 127-144.
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS ..., p. 205, for Kiley's comments on this project.
  - McCall's Magazine/Urban Redevelopment Study, / Date(s): 1948; Folder: 0138; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 94x68cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Drawing by DK in pensil and colored pencil bears stamp "Oscar Stonorov."
    Note: Note in Works indicates [Louis] Kahn and [?] Sorenson were associated architects.
  - Joseph Cotrufo Apartment, / Date(s): 1948; Tube: 0143; / Quantity: 5 / Dimensions: 58x43cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Remodeling drawings, bearing DK's registration stamp.
  - Macomber (Blair) Residence, / Date(s): 1948; Folder: 0145; / Quantity: 31 / Dimensions: <141x66cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Included with architectural drawings by DK are land and building surveys.
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS..., p. 206 for an account by Kiley of this remodeling job.
  - Hamilton Prefab, / Date(s): 1948 - 1949; Folder: 0155; / Quantity: 6 / Dimensions: <104x56cm. / Medium: Pencil11 / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Landscape plans and details; revisions to plans of prefabricated house; drawings dated 1949.
  - Zamore House, / Date(s): 1950; Folder: 0169; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 66x59cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Plans, sections and details fro garden walk and shelter; drawn by "G.P.S."
  - Dr. Barnet Fine Residence, / Date(s): 1950; Tube: 0172; / Quantity: 4 / Dimensions: 89x59cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site and planting plans with details drawings.
    Note: 5' grid on drawing #1, "Construction and Grading Plan."[
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS ..., p. 206 for an account by Kiley of this commission.
  - Dr. Henry Saltonstall Residence, / Date(s): 1950; Folder: 0173; / Quantity: 6 / Dimensions: <77x62cm. / Medium: Pencil; Blueline print / Support: Tracing paper; paper
    Note: Drawings by D.K.
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS ... ,p. 507.
  - Putney School Alumni Lodge, / Date(s): 1950 - 1952; Tube: 0180; / Quantity: 9 / Dimensions: <92x61cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Includes unnumbered working drawings.
  - Karl Schaffer Residence, / Date(s): 1950 - 1952; Folder: 0183; / Quantity: 16 / Dimensions: <100x77cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Published in: Featured in House and Home, March 1953, v. 3, pp. 150-155 and Interiors, May 1953, v. 112, pp. 90-93, 154.
  - Louis Baker Residence, / Date(s): 1950 - 1951; Folder: 0185; / Quantity: 4 / Dimensions: <107x67cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Drawings #1-#3 drawn by DK.
    Scale: Varies
    Published in: "A House in the Woods", Architectural Forum, December 1951, 95:6, pp. 101-107.
    Published in: Cf. THE COMPLETE WORKS ..., p. 206, for Kiley's account of his collaboration with architect Minoru Yamasaki.
  - Living Magazine Article, / Date(s): 1951; Folder: 0189; / Quantity: 2 / Dimensions: 76x34cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Tracing paper
    Scale: 1"=20'.
  - Kassler Prototype, / Date(s): 1951; Folder: 0190; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Sepia print / Support: Paper
    Note: Reversed sepia print (plan and elevation) labelled "Prototype Garden #1. Summer Scheme."
    Scale: 1/8"=1'.
    Published in: "Three Experiments in One House", House and Home, February 1955, v. 7, pp. 164-169.
  - Richard S. Gile Residence, / Date(s): 1951; Folder: 0191; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 45x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Drawn by D.K.
  - Echo Lake, / Date(s): 1951; Tube: 0196; / Quantity: 12 / Dimensions: 95x56cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Mixed
    Note: Preliminary and working drawings.
    Location of associated materials: Cf. also #5016, "Silver Lake".
  - Charles C. Withers Residence, / Date(s): 1951; Tube: 0198; / Quantity: 5 / Dimensions: 92x62cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Mixed
    Note: Includes ODK job #393.
    Note: Withers, an executive in the metalcrafting industry (Towle Silversmiths), was also the author of a standard study on architectural ironwork.
  - Richard A. Hunter Residence, / Date(s): 1951; Tube: 0202; / Quantity: 3 / Dimensions: <94x62cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: One drawing by D.K.
  - Charles Weston Residence, / Date(s): 1951; Tube: 0204; / Quantity: 7 / Dimensions: <107x67cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Location noted alternatively as "Franconia".
    Location of associated materials: Cf. #394; 1955 work on Weston property.
  - Rudolph Talbot Residence, / Date(s): 1951; Folder: 0205; / Quantity: 4 / Dimensions: <85x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing paper
    Note: Preliminary drawing drawn by DK.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #207, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0207; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 79x56cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #5.
    Location of associated materials: Cf. #5011-5013 for similar porch/screen design.
  - Aluminum Company of Canada / Alcan City, / Date(s): 1949 - 1952; Tube: 0216; / Quantity: 6 / Dimensions: <156x106cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Paper
    Note: File of prints, maps and surveys related to tthe planning of a new city of fifty thousand inhabitants.
  - Stanley Kaufman Residence, / Date(s): 1952; Tube: 0232; / Quantity: 21 / Dimensions: <94x66cm. / Medium: Mixed / Support: Mixed
    Note: Working drawings
  - Richardson Dwellings /United States Housing Authority, / Date(s): 1952; Folder: 0239; / Quantity: 4 / Dimensions: <152x76cm. / Medium: Ink / Support: Sepia prints
    Note: Project # D.C. 1-17.
    Published in: Cf. Berrizbeita, "Early Housing ...", in Dan Kiley: The Early Gardens, Princeton, 1999, pp. 21-37.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #184, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0251; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Diazotype / Support: Paper
    Note: Plan does not explictly identify D.U.K. as landscape architect.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #183, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0252; / Quantity: 3 / Dimensions: <77x61cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site and planting plans; together with detail drawings for porch and storage shed, identified as #2, B4, 2LB.
    Note: Obscured title block reading "Lou Bernard Voigt" appears on site plan recto.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #187, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0254; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan,identified as #2, B4, 2LB.
    Note:
    Note: Obscured title block reading "Lou Bernard Voigt" appears on plan recto.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #188, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0255; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/ planting plan identified as Unit #2 B4 2LB.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #189, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0256; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan identified as unit #2 B4 K4 S4.
    Note: Obscured title block reading "Lou Bernard Voigt" appears on recto of plan, overwritten "Dan Kiley".
    Scale: 1"=1-'.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #190, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0257; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #1 BE.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #192, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0258; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x56cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan; no unit indicated, only "Section 8".
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #193, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0259; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x55cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2 B4 KS4.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #194, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0260; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x55cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2B.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #195, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0261; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x55cm. / Medium: Xerox / Support: Paper
    Note: Poor quality repro of plan which bears "Lou Bernard Voigt" title block. Kiley's contribution unclear.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot#196, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0262; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Diazotype print / Support: Paper
    Note: No unit # indicated.
    Note: "Lou Bernard Voigt" title block; tho' definitely a Kiley design.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot#198, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0263; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x60cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan identified as Unit #6.
    Scale: 1"=10.,
  - Hollin Hills / Lot# 199, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0264; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x60cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #6.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #200, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0265; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x58cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #201, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0266; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #203, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0267; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #5B.
    Scale: 1"=1'.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #204, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0268; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x58cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #205, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0269; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x58cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2 B4 K4 S4.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #206, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0270; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 56x43cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan, with plant list, for Model House, Unit #2.
    Published in: Published in: House & Home, January 1954, pp. 140-143.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #209, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0272; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x55cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan marked "Prelom" for Unit #2.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #210, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0273; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x59cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #211, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0274; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site and planting information included on this nominal preliminary grading plan for Unit #2.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #212, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0275; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 75x58cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site and planting information included in this nominal grading plan for Unit #2B4 K4 S4.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #213, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0276; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x58cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planing plan for Unit #2 B4 2LB.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #214, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0277; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x56cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #191, / Date(s): 1955; Folder: 0278; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x56cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan with bench detail drawing. No unit indicated.
    Note: Obscured title block reading "Lou Bernard Voigt" appears on recto.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #215, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0279; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2 B4 2 LB.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #216, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0280; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 76x57 / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #217, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0281; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2 B4 K4.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #218, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0282; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x57cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #219, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0283; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 55x75cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #3.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot#220, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0284; / Quantity: item / Dimensions: 1 / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #5A.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #222, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0285; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x61cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan, with legend, for Unit #2 B4 2LB.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #223, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0286; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x60cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #225, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0287; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x65cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2 B4 2LB.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #227, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0288; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x58cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #228, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0289; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x59cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Planting/site plan for Unit #2.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #229, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0290; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x59cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan, with legend, for Unit #5B.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #230, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0291; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x61cm. / Medium: Pencil / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan for Unit #2 K4.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #231, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0292; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x58cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #233, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0293; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x61cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan; no Unit number indicated.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #234, / Date(s): 1953; Folder: 0294; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x60cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum
    Note: Site/planting plan, with legend. No Unit indicated.
  - Hollin Hills / Lot #235, / Date(s): 1954; Folder: 0295; / Quantity: 1 / Dimensions: 77x58cm. / Medium: Pencil; ink stamp / Support: Tracing vellum